What's wrong?
Tomorrow's soirée is our last one
before graduation, isn't it?
It is. Why?
I'm truly honored that you'll
be the one escorting me...
But are you sure it's all right?
Euphyllia, eh?
You don't need to worry about a thing.
Just let me take care of everything
when it comes to her.
Yes, but...
I'm sorry. I don't fully understand
the rules and etiquette of nobility.
Because you lived as a commoner before
Baron Cyan took you in as his daughter?
Yes.
After my mother died,
I was taken in by an orphanage.
But... it didn't work out very well.
People kept making strange passes at me,
or just plain bullying me...
so I've never been very good
at interacting with people.
Rejecting and failing to understand
someone alien to you...
The disconnect between
commoners and nobles...
This kingdom has become quite warped.
I want to change the Kingdom of Palettia.
I know you can do it, Prince Algard!
You can become a great king!
The previous king, my grandfather,
tried to change the kingdom, too.
But he failed.
With a half-hearted approach,
it would be impossible.
The road ahead of us will be a bumpy one.
Some unfortunate things might happen.
Despite that...
Will you still stay with me, Lainie?
Yes!
Prince Algard...
The Magical Revolution
of the Reincarnated Princess and the Genius Young Lady
Miss Lainie.
Do you not intend to drink your tea?
Oh... I-I'm sorry.
I'm... a vampire, aren't I?
And the only reason so many
people have been kind to me
is because I charmed them
without knowing it.
And yet, Miss Anis and her friends
treat me so well.
If you fret too much,
happiness will escape you.
But...
The more complicated a problem is,
the longer it persists.
But putting that aside, there is one problem
that you can resolve here and now.
What is it?
A maid's concern that the excellent tea
she brewed will go cold.
Right. Thank you.
It is indeed excellent.
You honor me with your praise.
Miss Il—
Quiet.
Remain calm and listen to me.
Someone just infiltrated the villa.
H-How could there be an intruder?
It's all right. Miss Anis will fly here
in response to the alarm immediately.
B-But Miss Anis left to speak before
the Ministry of the Arcane...
Yes, which is why we should
take refuge at the castle.
I can find my way around
the villa with my eyes closed.
Miss Lainie! That fog!
It might be poisonous! Don't inhale it!
We'll leave through the window!
Hold on tight!
As always, you do make quick judgments,
but you have a problem following through.
Fire Arrow!
Miss Ilia!
Why...
I won't apologize,
nor will I beg for forgiveness.
But...
It is unfortunate, Lainie.
With regard to the speech
by Duke Magenta's daughter,
as head of the Ministry of the Arcane,
I would like to stress one additional point.
Spirit contracts are the very
foundation of our kingdom!
This was because our first
king established this kingdom
by forging a direct contract
with a greater spirit.
I wanna go home...
Princess Anisphia.
The lecture you gave was magnificent.
Uh, thanks...
And who are you? I'm lost here.
I am Moritz Chartreuse.
He's the son of that old
geezer at the lecture!
And one of Al's flunkies, at that!
I caused a great deal of trouble for you
in the matter with Lady Euphyllia.
I wanted to apologize formally.
Why don't you apologize to her, then?
W-Well, yes, of course...
I'll be doing plenty of that later.
The truth is, I was the one
who proposed this lecture.
I hoped it would create an opportunity
to restore your reputation.
Wait, that was your idea?
Not the Ministry's?
Yes, so that you could do us
the favor of teaching us
about your magicology, an art that
was unappreciated until now.
I had hoped that could serve as my apology.
R-Right...
I have no idea what he's talking about.
What a weirdo.
I have no opinion on the matter.
There's no need to apologize to me.
But my conscience cannot accept that!
Please hear me out for another
ten minutes—no, an hour—
no, for eternity, if that's what
it takes to earn your forgiveness!
Huh? Is he a drunkard, too?
Please excuse me.
I need to go talk to my friend.
Your Highness's friend?
Please introduce me to them, as well!
And then we can all hear my father speak! Okay?
Yes! Let's do that!
In short...
Only descendants of the king who
made a contract with the spirits,
meaning those who can use magic,
have the right to rule this kingdom!
Regardless of how many sophistries
you may present us,
we will never acknowledge a heretic
who is incompatible with the spirits!
He's making no sense!
I'm scared! What's his deal?!
To tarnish our traditions
is to insult our kingdom!
Ilia!
Hey. Let go of me.
Get everyone in the venue together!
Don't let anyone leave!
I said let me go!
I can't do that!
Until we know what that sound was,
we cannot be imprud—
That sound was an alarm that I invented!
Something's happened at the villa!
All the more reason.
What?
No, Your Highness!
Please, calm yourself! Be rational!
What are you—
She's deranged!
Princess Anisphia has lost her mind!
Someone... Someone come help!
What?
I had a feeling this would happen someday,
and I was right! You are a bizarre,
dangerous individual!
You're on a rampage!
Consumed by debauchery!
Outrageously audacious and running rampant!
Restrain the deranged princess
and keep her in here!
Who are you...
calling "deranged"?!
L-Let me go! Let me go!
That's...
my line!
A d-dragon!
Wh-What are you doing?!
Restrain this monstrous princess at once!
You...
monster!
E-Euphyllia!
Miss Anis!
The window nearest the villa!
What's all this, now?
You all seem to be having such a good time.
Tilty!
A revolt? Is this a revolt?
If that's what it is, I'll take you on.
So go even wilder, won't you?!
Such skillful composite magic...
You'd better get out of here quick,
or I'll tie everyone up.
What are you doing, Tilty, you idiot?
Are you an idiot?!
I'm telling you to leave things here to me!
Just don't take it too far.
Euphie!
Right!
Wind Cutter!
Let's fly!
Do it!
Honestly...
You'd better do things right,
Anis, you idiot.
Oh, you're still on your feet?
No one asked you to get involved.
Must every last one of you...
keep ruining my plans?!
You insolent little girls,
and your disregard for our traditions!
Euphie! Over there!
No matter what I do or how I do it,
must you always stand in my way...
Sister?
What in the world is the meaning
of this, Prince Algard?
Keep it down, Euphyllia.
Miss... Anis...
I'm... sorry...
Don't apologize. Lainie!
I-I...
Hang in there.
You'll be fine. Just stay with me.
Prince Al... Magicite...
I know. Leave the rest to me.
Euphie!
Look after them.
I can help Ilia, but Lainie...
Lainie is a vampire.
She still has a chance.
But she's clearly had her
magicite ripped out!
Still, do everything you can. Please.
Finished talking?
How noble of you to wait for me.
I'm used to waiting.
I waited years for this moment, after all.
Were you the one behind the
lecture event at the Ministry?
Wasn't that Moritz's idea?
To get me away from the villa, yes.
If you had the backing of the Ministry,
that must mean its leader, Chartreuse,
was working with you, too.
Was he, now?
I'm amazed you could do all that
even under Lainie's fascination.
I still hold her in the
highest regard, of course.
And what of it?
Royalty should never let their emotions
lead them into poor decisions.
That's been drilled into me all my life,
as the one and only heir to the throne.
So you'd just take Lainie's magicite
from her without a second thought?
Yes. My emotions are secondary.
And you think becoming a vampire
is the right thing for royalty to do?!
You're the last one
I want to hear that from.
What is that on your back, pray tell?
You may not have absorbed
the magicite in the same way,
but we both sought the powers of monsters—
a vampire and a dragon—
just the same.
You and I are in very different positions.
That's right!
You're a princess who threw away your
right to the throne like it was nothing,
and I'm the one and only crown prince
who was left behind!
Our positions are different!
Al...
That's why I had no choice but to do this.
I will use the power of a vampire
to seize control of this kingdom.
Seize control?
But why?! You'd still be the next king,
even if you hadn't done that!
If you sincerely believe that,
you really have been oblivious.
How many people have truly
accepted me as the next king?
You can't tell me you haven't
heard people saying,
"If only Princess Anisphia
had a talent for magic"!
Everyone acknowledges you,
ridicules you, and fears you.
You are genuinely a monster.
You're wrong.
No ordinary human can
match up to a monster.
So I have no choice but to become one!
If there's no other way, then so be it!
You're wrong! That's not the kind of king
people want you to be!
Can't you just treasure the ties
that bind people to each other,
and be a king who works hand-in-hand
with them to lead the kingdom?!
A king like that can only
be called ornamental!
The ties that bind people?
Working hand-in-hand?
Well, I... I've seen it!
The rifts that gape between
commoner and commoner!
The arrogance of nobles who don't
even see commoners as people!
In this kingdom, magic is everything!
Which is why you should be
a king who changes that!
It can't be changed!
What happened when the previous king
extolled commoners
and gave them noble titles?!
A revolt!
One that involved many of the nobles!
Even now, after Father and Duke put it down,
its flames still smolder!
This kingdom is ill.
So I have no choice but to change it
with absolute power.
Power great enough to shatter
the unchangeable norm.
But...
I couldn't do it.
Al?
I'm a foolish commoner
who doesn't even compare to you.
I couldn't excel in anything.
I could do nothing.
No matter how hard I tried,
all I could do was things that were
possible if I just worked at them.
And that's why you sought power,
even if you had to steal it?
It's power that is necessary
to correct this misguided kingdom.
And you have no right to say
a single thing about it.
Anisphia Wynn Palettia.
You are the first princess,
and you threw away the responsibilities
burned into that name.
This is the future you chose not to pursue.
If it's something a monster
could throw away so easily,
what problem is there with a foolish
commoner like me vomiting blood
for the chance to pick it up?
Al, tell me one thing.
What is magic to you?
It's a curse, Sister.
Magic, the royal blood,
my position as a prince...
To me, they're all curses.
They're meant to reduce me to nothing.
I see.
Fine, Algard.
Maybe the place where you stand right now
is something I threw away.
But I can't allow that.
If you're going to pick up the
future that I threw away,
then I'll pick up the present
that you just threw away.
A kingdom ruled by an inhumane king
who hurts people and
tramples them underfoot
is not a kingdom where
people can live happily.
None are more unfortunate than a people
ruled by a king who lacks power!
Power? How very comical.
Are you really so vain as
to believe you can beat me
when we fight on equal ground?!
How dare you?!
If power really is everything,
then let's see you beat me!
I told you that you do not have
the right to stand in my way!
No. I will stop my brother's little game.
That's my right as your older sister!
It's too late for that nonsense now!
Yes, it really is... too late.
But, you know...
Magic is made up of prayers for tomorrow
and wishes for everyone's happiness, Al.
Sister...
Face me, Algard!
I reject your definition!
Episode Eight
The Magic Definition of the
Monster and the Commoner
Episode Nine
The Sister and Brother, and for
Whom the Crown Is Intended